A Guide to the Rockefeller University records, Auxiliary Services, Reproductions Supplied by Other Institutions or Individuals FA850
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller University records, Auxiliary Services, Reproductions Supplied by Other Institutions or Individuals
1924-1981
Rockefeller Archive Center
Cornell University. Medical College
New York University
Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research
Cornell University
Rockefeller University
FA850
1 Box(es)
1 box.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements note
Materials requiring specialized equipment for access (film, audio, video, slides) may be closed to research dependent on availability of the applicable equipment
Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
File Plan note
Former Classification: I 890
Conditions Governing Access note
This collection is open for research.
Medical sciences; Medical research; Life sciences; Cell and biomolecular sciences; Women’s history; Biochemistry; Architecture; Biology -- Research; Women; Medical education; Medicine, Preventive; Science -- Study and teaching; Cornell University. Medical College; New York University; Rockefeller Institute for Medical Research; Cornell University; Rockefeller University
- American Philosophical Society (correspondence), 1946-1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Library: Edward L. Tatum correspondence in APS collections.
- American Philosophical Society (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Library: Guide to the Erwin Chargaff Collection.
- Lenox Hill Neighborhood Association
  - 1924 1928 1935-1936 1939 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Copies of selected pages from the Annual Reports of 1924, 1928, 1935-36, 1939; also from "LHNA. Its History and Work. A Story of Service... November 1928"
    Loaned through the courtesy of Mrs. Celine Marcus, Director.
  - 1924 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Copy negatives of 6 photographs, 1924 and ca. 1920s (filed with main photograph collection).
  - Seymour S. Cohen, "Some Contributions of the Princeton Laboratory of the Rockefeller Institute on Proteins, Viruses, Enzymes, and Nucleic Acids", 1978 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    In: Symposium on the Origins of Modern Biochemistry; a Retrospect on Proteins, New York Academy of Sciences, 1978. The origins of modern biochemistry. (Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences; v. 325) [pp. 303-306. 193] P.R. Srinivasan, Joseph F. Fruton, and John T. Edsall, editors. [reprinted? ].
  - The Max Delbrück Laboratory Dedication Ceremony. Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory, Saturday, August 29, 1981; [Booklet] 24 pp. with photographs (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Sir Charles Harington, "The Place of the Research Institute in the Advance of Medicine" reprinted from The Lancet, June 28 1958, pp. 1345-1351, 1958 June 28 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    [Photocopy from the National Institute for Medical research Council Library, London[?]].
- From Rockefeller Archive Center, Rockefeller family collections (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Immediate Source of Acquisition note
  (received September 1986, T. Rosenbaum).
  - Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller, 1949-1952
    General, 1949-1950 General, 1951-1952. Box 43, Folder 424.
  - Herbert S. Gasser / John. D. Rockefeller, Jr. covering letter for memorandum requested by Mr. Rockefeller, 1950 October 13
    [see Scientific Reports, R.G. 439 (RU Archives), vol. 39].
  - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. / Herbert S. Gasser, (copy) acknowledges Dr. Gasser's memorandum and requests clarification, 1951 February 28
- Johns Hopkins Archives, 8 items (Box 1, Folder 7)
  See Hospital. 430. 12 re photocopies on Nancy P. Ellicott, Hospital Superintendent.
- Bettmann Archive. 2 1925 views of RIMR. Stored with Chronol. photo file of RIMR campus/neighborhood photographs (Box 1, Folder 7)
- "A Guide to the Manuscript Sources in the History of Medicine in the American Philosophical Society" by J. Stephen Catlett, 1987 revised version (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Final Report: Television Broadcasts: American Association for the Advancement of Science, Annual Meeting, Boston, Massachusetts, December 26-31, 1969 (Chapter 4: Interconnection with Rockefeller University - New York City), 1969 December 26-31 (Box 1, Folder 9)